we've been given
five expressions and we're going to
examine each expression
and determine whether it will return
true or false
so taking a look at the expression on
line one
we are comparing whether 32 times 4
is greater than or equal to 129
32 times 4 is equal to 128
so this expression will return false
128 is not greater than or equal to 129.
and i'm going to paste that expression
into irb so we can see that
moving on to our next expression on line
three
false is not equal to not true
so what is not true when we use the
not operator in front of a boolean it
will return
the opposite boolean so in this case
not true is false
so the expression on line 3 reads as
false is not
equal to false and that will return
false the boolean false is equal to the
boolean false
again we'll bring this expression over
to irb
moving on to line 5 we're comparing true
to the integer 4 true is equal to 4.
4 is a truthy value meaning that
when used in a conditional it will
evaluate as
true however it's not equal to the
boolean
true so this expression will also return
false
i'll paste it into irb and we see that
false return value
moving on to line seven we first need to
evaluate the comparison in parentheses
we're comparing 847 to the string 874.
an integer will never be equal to a
string so this will evaluate to false
on the left side of our comparison here
on line 7 we also have false
so this expression reads as false is
equal to false
and that will return true
and we paste it into irb and see that
our last expression here on line 9 is a
little bit more difficult to parse
this expression uses the or operator
when using the logical or operator if
any of the expressions that we provide
return true
then the entire expression will return
true
we can see at the end of line 9 that we
have
false so now let's examine each
expression within the parentheses
on the left side of this logical or
operation
the first expression is not true
which evaluates to false
moving on to the next expression 100
divided by 5 is 20.
again we have the not operator here
so we're comparing the equality of not
to 20. not 20 evaluates as
false so false is not equal to 20.
we can move on to examine the next
expression
in this expression we're comparing 328
divided by 4
to the integer 82. 328 divided by 4
equals 82 so this equality comparison
will return
true meaning that the entire expression
on line 9
returns true
i'll paste that in and we see the return
value of true
you